Hi everyone. We have general manager
James Gladstone available. Please raise
your hand if you have a question.
We can start with Jamal then move to
Demetrius.
>> What's going on James? How you doing?
>> Life is good. How are you guys?
>> Pretty good out here at TC. So, uh,
might have to pull you out here. Uh,
what do you like about Chris Rodriguez?
>> Uh, I think there's a lot to like. you
know, uh, obviously
Liam has some familiarity with him
dating back to his time at Kentucky. Uh,
beyond that, it's kind of fun like if I
unravel
sort of diving into who he's been as a
professional football player and get
into the the nuances of our exposure to
him in the leadup to the decision to to
prioritize him as a an untendered RFA.
It was uh, you know, it's interesting
when we watch players. Uh Tony Belli's
been a
a consistent presence in that, but you
know, he's fallen into the the line of
if you watch the tape right before
sharing his perspective uh on each
player and uh and we've kind of fallen
into that becoming a a funny comment
knowing that he's usually talking to a
group of people that have watched the
tape. And uh and so with that, Chris
Rodriguez is in fact somebody that if
you watch the tape, you understand uh
very quickly exactly who he is as a
football player. Uh the superpowers that
he taps into consistently and uh you
know, if you draw back to his time at
Kentucky, uh it's remained a constant.
He is uh he's very physical at the point
of attack. Uh he has a really good pace
in his approach to the line of scrimmage
and finding the lanes. uh obviously an
intimate understanding of the system and
how Liam likes to call things. Uh so
there's a lot of strong matches just
generally from how uh you know those two
in tandem can really work together and
then al also our interest in continuing
to find ways to level up our capacity in
the run game to you know make it a
really balanced attack being able to
attack the perimeter and also the inside
uh in really uh you know fair and
balanced forms. And I think that Chris
seamlessly provides that.
>> Can you talk team building philosophy
briefly? I mean, uh, kind of quiet
through free agency. There's been that
frenzy and Jaguars fans not necessarily
used to it. So, maybe a little bit of
frantic waiting for you to do something
there,
>> man. Quite a bit different than, you
know, a year ago today, right? We came
out the gates what you might call us
hot. Signed in double digit free agents,
external free agents right off the bat a
year ago. And you know, the whole
approach to that cycle was raise the
floor of the football team and that was
a part of it. Um, we're at a stage now
where uh, you know, a higher volume of
draft capital is what we're hunting up
and those compensatory picks. When you
think about highriced free agents of
ours ended up signing elsewhere, uh,
welldeserved contracts, I mean, a lot of
guys that have already announced his
signing, I mean, they've did their part
to put themselves in really sound
positions to earn that and excited for
all those guys. In return, by not
signing any outside free agents, we
recoup 2027 draft capital. And I think
on its surface you would think, oh,
okay, you're going to make picks in
2027. Whereas in reality, those draft
picks and having more of them actually
allows you the luxury of remaining in
the hunt at different intervals
throughout the entire calendar year for
acquiring players. You think about
training camp a year ago and using a day
three pick to acquire a wide receiver in
Tim Patrick. you think about ahead of
the trade deadline and being able to use
two picks on day three to acquire a wide
receiver and Jacobe Meyers without that
draft capital at your disposal. Uh you
may not be as willing or able to
relinquish some of those future picks.
So by building that up now, it allows us
the luxury of remaining uh sort of with
the flexibility to do those sorts of
things as we move into the next stages
of the off seasonason and into the
regular season.
>> J,
>> we'll go to Demetrius, then to Brent.
Hey, James, you you sort of touched on
this with the comp picks, but in in
terms of uh I guess letting for lack of
a better term, uh Devin Lloyd Walk, how
challenging was that for you guys? Um
and just, you know, how does that sort
of change the outlook of the linebacker
room moving forward?
>> Yeah, I think Devin's impact on our
football team over the course of the
last year uh was nothing short of, you
know, significant. And without him,
without his on ball production, games
are going to look a lot different. The
results of those games are going to look
a lot different. Um, and I know that our
coaching staff had such a high
appreciation uh for what he did. The
players in the locker room love to play
beside him uh and appreciate all the
pieces that he brought to the puzzle. Uh
beyond that, I think we can look at our
own that we still have as people that
can step in and have stepped in uh over
the course of their rookie contracts.
And Ventrell Miller, uh he started
multiple games uh at linebacker for us
and did so even last year. And beyond
that, Branson Combmes, who is an
undrafted college free agent, found his
mark on special teams and still has a
lot uh of upside that can be built upon.
You know, beyond that, you look at the
middle linebacker spot in Foyer, who's
held that down for quite a few years and
is the the leader of that crew is, you
know, it's really exciting to know that
he can continue to evolve in that
capacity with Jack Kaiser right behind
him and then, you know, the fact that we
were able to get Dennis back who wasn't
a signing until after the draft last
year and uh really made his dent within
the really flexible role that is Sam
Backer. being able to rush, being able
to drop, being able to really be active
on special teams and bring a competitive
fire that you know anybody who loves
football will love Dennis Gard and uh
you know I think that was pretty clear
and he you know he allowed Campy who
really appreciates that Sam Ber position
to grow it and really make it so that
was suited for you know what Dennis does
best and then right behind him you got
uh you know Mloud who's coming off of
really a red shirt year dealing uh with
his injuries and then also Yes, Abdullah
who's obviously been such a critical
piece in particular on special teams.
So, there's a lot of experience coming
back with uh you know, obviously still
room to find ways to improve over the
course of the offseason, not including
just the draft.
>> Thank you.
>> We'll go to Brent then to O'Halerin.
Hey, James, as you know, uh there are a
lot of rumors that fly around and
reports this time of year, but uh uh
there were some, you know, reputable
reports over the weekend about you guys
being linked to Crosby before he got
traded or when he got traded to the
Ravens. Um is there any merit to it? And
how much are you guys still actively
trying to fortify potentially that
defensive front? Yeah, I think that's
going to be an ongoing process where
we're continuing to map out how we can
level up and you know that's a pairing
of personnel and scheme and uh also the
back end being tied to rush plans and
continuing to ensure that we're able to
stop the run at such a high tick like we
were last year without diluting that
element but still improving the pass
rush. Uh so that's a fun uh a fun piece
to this offseason to try to really map
out. Uh that wasn't uh necessarily
something that we were actively engaged
in. We're always communicating with
other clubs on uh you know the landscape
of their thoughts and I can tell you in
particular we never got down to a uh uh
a real dialogue exploring that.
>> One one followup if you don't mind. You
guys were active last year. You spent a
good amount of money. It's it's a chance
to get better uh this time of year as a
football team potentially. Is it hard to
be disciplined the way you guys uh were
this week or are you just almost kind of
forced to be disciplined the with the
nature of your cap situation?
>> Yeah, I think FOMO sets in a little bit.
You know, we're all human. Uh while at
the same time, it's not uncharted
territory for me. You know, it's not
uncharted territory for Liam. He was
with us at the Rams and you know this
was an approach that we took uh in
multiple cycles and it's really one that
I know well and feel confident can
navigate and really be able to use all
the different intervals that lie in
front of us to continue to shape what
will be the 2026 Jacksonville Jaguars.
So ex it's exciting from my vantage
point to know that uh you know the start
of the league year began yesterday
roughly 24 hours ago a little less uh
and it's nothing more than the start.
>> Thanks. Appreciate it.
>> Oh then to Drock.
>> Hey James, I got two for you. Uh first
one is Brian Thomas Jr. How intense has
interest from other teams been in
trading for him and have you even got an
offer yet?
No, we we haven't and there hasn't been
a ton of dialogue around that front. As
teams check in simply because it seems
like there's another word reputable came
up earlier, I don't think there's been
any reputable statement. Uh we don't uh
have any real action on any of those
fronts. And uh you know, as I think you
think back to where we landed at the end
of the season, uh where our passing
attack was, we have no interest in
disrupting the momentum. We look forward
to continuing to build off of where we
left things and uh know that Brian
Thomas is a is a big piece to that
puzzle and we don't we don't want to
make sure that that gets disrupted at
any time.
Then secondly for me, um, where you are
in the draft process, you have four
picks from 56 to 100, where you're at
with your evaluations, are your needs
going to match up with the strengths and
the sweet spots of those rounds two and
three?
>> Uh, that is a really fair question. I
think the best way to sort of think
about that is right now what we've
structured it to be is that we don't
have to pick based off of need
necessarily at any specific spot. Uh,
that's a luxury. I think when I was with
the Los Angeles Rams, there was there
were too many drafts and I got to live
this where you felt pressed to take a
specific position. And there were
instances where it worked out fine for
us. There were instances where it
didn't. And that may just be the draft.
It it may just be the way that those
specific situations unfolded. But I
think walking into the door on day two
as it stands right now, we're not saying
that we need this position at this spot.
Uh which is a luxury. And I I'm excited
about that. It means that we can really
take somebody that we understand that we
have a clear vision for alignment on and
it doesn't have to be dependent on it's
got to be at this specific spot or this
side of ball.
>> Gotcha. Thanks, James.
>> Thank you.
>> You're sorry, Emily. Hey James, um was
there an attempt to try and get or try
and resign Travis ETN? And um obviously
with him being gone, what's the level of
confidence you guys have in Tootton
being able to kind of be, you know, for
lack of a better term, the number one
guy?
>> Yeah, it's a fair question. We engaged
with his reps and monitored his market.
We approached it knowing that his uh his
contract was going to be pretty uh
pretty high and wanted to make sure that
uh we were never out of the loop on
that. And um you know, as things
progressed, we obviously made the
decision to to sort of step aside and
have him get what was earned. And I
think he's pretty darn excited, it
seems, to be back in his home state and
be able to step into that uh that that
stadium. And I I know for us it's really
exciting because
you know Bay Shaw was in a spot
obviously where he didn't receive the
bulk of the carries but certainly had
his moments to shine throughout the
course of the year and showcase you know
a good chunk of what he has to offer.
And outside of just Bashaw you got
Laquent who carved out a very clear role
and contribution to the football team.
bring in Chris. Uh, and you got a nice
little trio alongside, uh, DJ Dallas and
Jquwind Jackson. So, it's a it's a
really good crew that we feel confident
in at this stage. Uh, look forward to
seeing how things unfold throughout the
course of the spring and, you know,
allowing our coaches to get get hands-on
with Chris and see how that all takes
shape. But, as it stands, it's a it's a
fairly well-rounded uh, complimentary
group and we're excited about it.
And back to Brian Thomas real quick, are
you amused when you see rumors like that
just sort of take a life take on a life
of their own around the league when you
get to free agency or whatever it's like
this and then the next thing you know
there's like seven or eight people that
are talking about you know Brian Thomas
is available on the market or I mean do
do you guys even do you care? Does it
bother you when that's out there? What
what's the reaction when all that
happens?
>> It can be very strange for sure. I I
care more for, you know, what weight
that might put on Brian himself, right?
When, you know, it's it's something
that's entirely out of his control and
unnecessary. Uh, so I I think that's
where my mind would go if anything. But,
uh, you know, when it's fraudulent
claims, it's you just keep a you get,
you know, keep your mind on what you can
you can focus on and you can actually
control and and try to do what's best
for for the Jacksonville Jaguars. And
ultimately that's not the hardest thing
to do when you know that's the the role
and where you can try to
compartmentamentalize things. But yeah,
if anything it's it's hopefully it's not
a weight that uh comes with the player
that ever would be involved in in such a
thing.
>> Thank you.
>> We're working under time constraints. We
have time for just two more quick
questions. We can go to Rick and then to
Shipley.
>> How you doing James? Life is good. How
are you?
>> Good. I'm doing great. Uh just overall,
how are things different for you right
now? You were really thrown into it a
year ago when you got here with free
agency and and you guys made such a
dramatic turn as far as your roster and
then what 42 days away from the draft
just to have your own scouts in place,
pro personnel directors in place. How
different is this compared to one year
ago? Yeah, I think last year you were uh
you there was a lot of translation in
comparison. Uh not everybody's speaking
the same language and trying to bridge
that gap. This year uh it's very
seamless. dialogue is uh you know on the
same plane and it allows for uh you know
when communication's operating at a high
tick it allows decisions to uh you know
unfold in a way that you would you know
feel really confident in because of that
right there's clarity that comes with
that so there's a lot of energy that I
look back on a year ago that was applied
to bridging the gap and uh you know a
lot of parallel modes of operation that
were being brought together but this is
now uh a situation where everybody's
walking down the same track. Uh so that
allows it to be a little bit more
efficient.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks for asking.
>> Last one. Shipley.
>> Hey James, thanks for doing this. Uh
just because I don't believe we've asked
about him yet. Buster Brown, bringing
him back. Just how much flexibility does
that give you? You mentioned that you
know you don't feel like you have a need
really being forced. I mean, just
knowing you guys now have several guys
at cornerback to where that's not like
something glaring heading into April.
>> Yeah. A ton. So Jack to have Buster back
and you know his interest in being back
existed and you know when it's such a a
strong match both parties really
interested in bringing that to life you
know Buster's in a position where he's
finally got a chance to play with the
same defensive coordinator in
back-to-back seasons and build off of
what was a really strong schematic and
skill set you know tie and I know him
and coach Camp have a really close
relationship um you know he's just
starting a family and to to have
consistency is is not a bad thing. And
you know, everybody feels like, you
know, he's just touching touching the
floor what he can do in this system.
And, you know, feel really excited about
what he'll be able to do as he builds
off of the momentum that, you know, he
was able to to showcase. and then the
rest of the group as a whole. It just it
brings with it some stability that uh
you know allows everybody to operate at
a high clip and you know feel uh assured
going into the off season that you know
that's not something that we got to be
uh thinking much of uh as it relates to
decisions moving forward.
>> Thanks James. Heck
>> yeah. Thanks for asking.